<?xml version="1.0"?>
<block>
  <name>Runtime CFO Control</name>
  <key>mods_runtime_cfo_ctrl</key>
  <category>Synchronizers</category>
  <import>import mods</import>
  <make>mods.runtime_cfo_ctrl($avg_len, $abs_cfo_threshold, $rf_center_freq)</make>
  <param>
    <name>Avg Transitory Length</name>
    <key>avg_len</key>
    <type>int</type>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Abs CFO Threshold</name>
    <key>abs_cfo_threshold</key>
    <type>float</type>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Nominal RF Center Freq.</name>
    <key>rf_center_freq</key>
    <type>float</type>
  </param>
  <sink>
    <name>freq_offset_in</name>
    <type>float</type>
  </sink>
  <sink>
    <name>mean_fo_est</name>
    <type>float</type>
  </sink>
  <sink>
    <name>var_fo_est</name>
    <type>float</type>
  </sink>
  <source>
    <name>freq_offset_out</name>
    <type>float</type>
  </source>
  <source>
    <name>rf_center_freq</name>
    <type>float</type>
  </source>
  <doc>Runtime Carrier Frequency Offset Control

Observes carrier frequency offset (CFO) estimations and makes sure that the \
the CFO is always within a correctable range. A CFO threshold is configured to this \
block and relates to the maximum CFO that can be estimated and, consequently, \
corrected in software. Once the CFO estimation at the input exceeds the threshold, \
the block changes the RF center frequency that should be used to alter the frequency \
in hardware (e.g. in the USRP/RTL) instead.

The reason why this block is used is because CFO estimation algorithms are only able \
to estimate CFOs within a certain range. In order to keep the CFO always within this \
range, one solution is to update the RF center frequency every time it exceeds the  \
range. Once the center frequency itself is changed, the CFO with respect to the new \
center frequency (and not to the nominal center freq.) is close to 0, so that the \
CFO estimation algorithm will continue to be able to estimate the forthcoming CFOs \
properly. Note that this is useful when the CFO changes significantly over time, for \
example in the case when low-stability LNBs are used for satellite reception.

This block also combines well with a CFO estimation algorithm that relies on \
averaging when outputing CFO estimations. The *avg_len* parameter of this \
block is used to ensure that the output CFO estimation (the post-processed \
one) is non-zero only after the averaging transitory has passed.

Parameters:
avg_len           -> Transitory length of the CFO estimation averaging
abs_cfo_threshold -> Threshold for the absolute value of the CFO
rf_center_freq    -> Nominal (or starting) RF center frequency
  </doc>
</block>
